courthousenews.com 2016-11-05

# Courthouse News Service Privacy Policy

**Courthouse News Service Privacy Policy**

Policy version date: August 1, 2011

Courthouse News Service (" **Courthouse News** ," “ **Us** ,” or “ **We** ”) wishes to offer the users of its web sites a personalized and interactive experience.  At the same time, Courthouse News is  committed to protecting the privacy of information that users provide to Courthouse News through its web sites.  This Privacy Policy explains how Courthouse News and others use the information received when you use Courthouse News’ web sites.  This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by or through Courthouse News’ web sites and does not apply to information obtained by Courthouse News through other means. 

This Privacy Policy applies to the following web sites:

[Courthouse News Service](http://www.courthousenews.com/) (www.courthousenews.com)

[Entertainment Law Digest](http://www.entlawdigest.com/) (www.entlawdigest.com)

_Securities Law Report_ (www.cnssecuritieslaw.com)

_Environmental Law Report_ (www.cnsenvironmentallaw.com)

_Walt_ _ Girdner_ ([www.waltgirdner.com](http://www.waltgirdner.com/))

_Kaiser Bad News_ (www.kaiserbadnews.com)

The web sites listed above are each a “ **Site** ,” and referred to collectively as the “ **Sites**.” 

Amendments to this Privacy Policy will be posted on the Sites and will be effective when posted.  Your continued use of the Sites following the posting of any amendment will constitute your acceptance of that amendment.  See the “Changes to the privacy policy” section below for further information.

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact Courthouse News by e-mail at csage@courthousenews.com. 

**Registered users**

Registration is not mandatory to access the public areas of the Sites.  However, registration may be required to access certain areas of the Sites or the products and services provided through those areas of the Sites.  The areas of the Sites requiring registration are noted on each Site.  When registering, users may be provided with a user name and password.  Courthouse News is not responsible for any loss or misuse of your user name and password.  Always remember that in order to protect your privacy you should not share your user name or password with others. 

You may change, delete or deactivate information provided through the registration process by e-mailing us at csage@courthousenews.com or writing to us at Courthouse News Service, 30 North Raymond Avenue, Suite 310, Pasadena, CA 91103.

**Personally identifiable information**

We may collect personally identifiable information from you automatically when you access the Sites, as well as through your voluntary actions while visiting the Sites.  For example, we collect personally identifiable information from you when you register with a Site, submit a comment, use a Site to make purchases, send us an e-mail, or use a Site to make changes to one or more of your Courthouse News subscriptions.  The particular information we collect from you will depend on the particular pages of the Sites you visit as well as the particular features of the Sites you choose to use.  We will not share this information with anyone outside of Courthouse News except as set forth in this Privacy Policy or as disclosed at the time the information is collected.  Personally identifiable information we may collect from you may include, by way of example:

            ●  _Your name_ ;  
●  _Internet Protocol address_ ;  
●  E-mail address;   
●  Contact information (including address, zip code, country, and phone number);  
●  Company or business affiliation;  
●  Financial information, such as account or credit card numbers;   
●  User name and password information collected during the registration process;  
●  Other personal information provided to us as part of a comment, discussion forum, e-mail, or other similar communication or post.

YOU SHOULD NOT PROVIDE COURTHOUSE NEWS WITH ANY PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION (OR SUBMIT OR POST ANY PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION TO ANY OF THE SITES) UNLESS YOU WOULD LIKE THAT INFORMATION TO BE USED AND SHARED BY COURTHOUSE NEWS IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS POLICY.  LIKEWISE, YOU SHOULD NOT PROVIDE PERSONAL INFORMATION AS PART OF A COMMENT, DISCUSSION FORUM, OR OTHER SIMILAR POST TO ANY OF THE SITES UNLESS YOU WANT THAT INFORMATION TO BE ACCESSIBLE BY OTHER USERS OF THE SITE, AS INFORMATION PROVIDED AS PART OF A COMMENT, DISCUSSION FORUM, OR OTHER SIMILAR POST MAY BE AVAILABLE TO OTHER USERS OF A SITE.

**Use of personally identifiable information**

The personally identifiable information that Courthouse News receives from users of the Sites (both registered and unregistered users) may be used for a variety of purposes, for example to improve the content of the Sites, to customize content and/or layout of the Sites for each individual user of the Sites, to notify users of the Sites about updates to and activities on the Sites and about goods and services that we feel may be of interest to users, to analyze data and patterns regarding usage of the Sites, and to contact users of the Sites.  Personally identifiable information may also be used and shared for the purpose of providing the user with any requested information, products, or services. 

Courthouse News may contract with third parties to provide various services relating to the Sites on an outsourced basis.  For example, we may contract with an e-mail provider to handle the distribution of e-mail messages to or from users of a Site, a web site hosting provider to host all or a portion of a Site, or some other third party to process payments for the products and services we offer.  Courthouse News may provide personally identifiable information received from users of its Sites to these third party providers for the purpose of enabling these third party providers to provide these outsourced services to Courthouse News. 

As our business develops, we reserve the right to display advertisements on our Sites.  In the event we display advertising on our Sites, you should be aware that third party advertisers may receive certain personally identifiable information about you if you click on any advertisements that may be displayed on the Sites (and clicking on any advertisement displayed on the Sites will be considered your consent to “opt in” for this transfer).  In addition, we reserve our right to combine and enhance the personally identifiable information we receive from users of our Sites with other data and information we obtain from third parties for such purposes as improving our advertising. 

**Disclosure and use of personally identifiable information as required by law**

We may use and/or disclose personally identifiable information where it is necessary to enforce a subscriber agreement, our terms of use for the Sites, or to otherwise enforce or protect Courthouse News’ rights under applicable law, including, without limitation, Courthouse News’ intellectual property rights.  We may also need to use and/or disclose personally identifiable information about certain users of the Sites when we have a reasonable and good-faith belief that such use or disclosure is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order, or legal process served on Courthouse News or the Sites.  

While this Privacy Policy describes ways you can opt-out of some uses of personally identifiable information (see the “Choice and opt-out” section, below), you may not opt-out of the uses of personally identifiable information described in this section. 

**E-mails you may receive from us or our partners**

_Service Announcements_. ****  On occasion it may be necessary to send out service related announcements.  For instance, if our Sites or any of the services offered through the Sites are temporarily suspended for maintenance, Courthouse News or its partners might send an e-mail to users.  These communications are not promotional in nature.  Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications.

_Special Offers and Updates_ **.**  Courthouse News or its partners may send new registrants of a Site a welcoming e-mail to verify password and username.  Users who provide us with an e-mail address or other contact information may occasionally also receive information on products, services, special deals, and/or other information.  Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications.  Please see the “Choice and opt-out” section below. 

**Choice and opt-out**

You may opt-out of receiving certain e-mail, mail or telephone calls from us.  As noted above, you may not-opt out of the uses of personally identifiable information described in the section above entitled “Disclosure and use of personally identifiable information as required by law.”  In addition, you may not opt-out of receiving e-mail service announcements.

All opt-out requests can be made by e-mailing us at csage@courthousenews.com or writing to us at Courthouse News Service, 30 North Raymond Avenue, Suite 310, Pasadena, CA 91103.

**Subscribers to Courthouse News’ reports**

If you are a subscriber to Courthouse News’ reports, you may review and change certain personal information relating to your subscription by clicking on the “subscribers” link on the www.courthousenews.com home page. 

**Non-personally identifiable information**

Like many web sites, our server, where possible, automatically recognizes each visitor’s Internet Protocol address _._   Our servers may also collect other information about how visitors use the Sites (for example, what pages are viewed, what products and services are purchased, or the length of time that users stay on the Sites).  This information is generally collected and maintained in anonymous and in a non-personally identifiable form and it allows us to do such things as improve the content of the Sites, facilitate market research, and ensure that subscriber agreements are not abused.  We may utilize the services of a third party to help us understand this information better, and the information that is disclosed to these entities will usually remain in an anonymous and non-personally identifiable form.  ****

**Cookies and web beacons**

We may use cookies or similar technology for various purposes to facilitate and enhance interaction with the Sites.  “Cookies” are small files that are placed on an individual computer’s hard drive to enable the person using that computer to more easily communicate and interact with the Sites.  Some of the ways we may use cookies are to save user preferences, to record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, and to record session information, such as items that users add to their shopping cart.  Courthouse News does not use cookies to retrieve information from a computer that is unrelated to Courthouse News or the Sites.

A cookie does not collect or keep your name or other personally identifiable information; however, we may link the information obtained through cookies to other personally identifiable information to give us a better understanding of your preferences, so that we can provide a more meaningful experience to you on our Sites. 

We may also use web beacons (also known as web bugs, pixel tags or clear GIFs), an often transparent graphic image placed on a web site that is used to monitor the behavior of users visiting web sites. 

We may use an outside advertisement serving company to display advertisements on the Sites.  The advertisement serving company may also use web beacons, and may also place and collect cookies when it displays an advertisement on the Sites.  Those web beacons and cookies are controlled by the outside advertisement serving company, and users should refer to that provider’s privacy policy for further information regarding its use of web beacons and cookies.

**Links to other web sites**

The web sites of third parties not affiliated with Courthouse News may be accessible through the Sites.  For example, a news story or column may provide a link to a third party’s web site.  In addition, third party advertisers may receive certain personally identifiable information about you if you click on advertisements displayed on the Sites.  These third party web sites have their own privacy and data collection policies and practices.  Courthouse News is not responsible for any actions or privacy policies of such third parties.  You should check the applicable privacy policies of those third parties when providing personally identifiable information through linked web sites or advertisements.

**Children**

The Sites are not intended for children under the age of 13, and Courthouse News does not knowingly solicit, collect, or store personally identifiable information from or about children under the age of 13.  If we discover that we have inadvertently collected any information from a child under 13, we will delete such information immediately.  Please contact us at csage@courthousenews.com if you believe that we have received personally identifiable information from or about a child under 13.

**Security**

We will use reasonable security measures on the Sites to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control.  While there is no such thing as perfect security on the Internet, we will take all reasonable steps to insure the safety of your personal information.  For example, only those individuals who need your personally identifiable information to perform a specific job are granted access to that personally identifiable information.  Furthermore, the servers on which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment. 

**Changes to this privacy policy**

This Privacy Policy is subject to change.  If we decide to change this Privacy Policy, we will post material changes on the Sites so our users are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and if we disclose it.  Unless we seek and receive your consent, we will use your personally identifiable information in accordance with the version of the Policy in effect at the time the information was collected.  Your continued use of the Sites following the posting of any amendment to the Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of that amendment. 

**Transfer of information**

If Courthouse News elects, in its reasonable discretion, to transfer ownership or control of a Site or the Sites to a third party, whether or not in the context of an acquisition of Courthouse News or a merger of Courthouse News with a third party, you consent to the transfer of your personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information by Courthouse News to that third party, provided that all use of your information by that third party remains subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy.   ****

**Thank you for visiting the Sites.   ******

**Effective date:   August 1, 2011**
